# Mimansha Jha

mimansha1600@gmail.com | 7001274757 | Chennai, India

## Summary

Innovative Web Development/UI-UX Student with experience in front-end and interface development, including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP. Strengths include quick thinking and problem-solving skills. Detail-driven individual with the intention of exceeding expectations and improving project growth.

#### **Education**

## **SRM Institute Of Science and Technology**

Sep 2022 - Present

B.Tech · Computer Science with Business Systems · Chennai

9.06

#### North Point Senior Secondary School

Apr 2021 - Jun 2022 379/500

12th · CBSE · Kolkata

# The Cambridge School

Apr 2019 - Mar 2020

10th · IGCSE · Kolkata

559/700

## **Experience**

Bharat Intern | Welcome Letter

May 2023 - Jun 2023

Web Development · Intern · Virtual Internship Program

Online

#### Google For Developers | Certificate

Apr 2023 - Jun 2023

Android Developer Virtual Internship · Intern · Learning

Online

# **Projects**

· Arduino

#### **Sports League Management**

601

· Python, OOP, MySQL

SQL

Mini Project - utilized Python for data structures, OOP, file handling, and automation, and MySQL for database design, querying, and data management in the Sports League Management project.

#### **Dual Axis Solar tracker**

Semi-Conductor

'Best Working Model' at TechKnow Contest - utilized skills in microcontroller programming, sensor integration, motor control, and circuit design to optimize solar panel orientation for maximum energy efficiency.

#### **Self Tracking Line Car**

· Motor Driver Circuit

Microcontroller Programming

Applied skills in microcontroller programming, sensor integration, motor control, real- time processing, and circuit design to create autonomous line-following vehicles.

# Integrating Sustainability into Corporate Strategy: A Path to Long-Term Competitive Advantage

Sep 2024 - Present

Dr. Nagalakshmi M.V.N. (Corresponding author) · Management & Implementation

**Business Strategy** 

## **Portfolio**

Jun 2024 - Present

· CSS, JS

Web Development

## **Certifications**

#### Introduction to Data Analytics course | Certificate

Dec 2024 -

# AWS Machine Learning Foundations Course | Certificate

Feb 2024 -

Networking Basics | Badge

CISCO

**AWS** 

Oct 2024 -

# Volunteering

#### **Raynagar Free Primary School**

Volunteer · Community Connect

May 2024 - Jun 2024

# **Competitions**

### **French Word Power**

First · Quebec Government Office, Mumbai

#### **Concours Romain Rolland**

Finalist · Alliance Française de Normandie, France

**Techknow Contest** Feb 2023

Winner · SRM Department of Nanotechnology

# **Conferences and Workshops**

#### **Activation Workshop on Metaverse and Extended Reality**

**AICTE** 

#### Design and Develop Workshop for UI/UX

Google Developer Student Clubs · SRM

## **Extra Curricular Activities**

SRM MUN Society Oct 2023 - Aug 2024

Next Gen AI Oct 2024 -

#### **Skills**

Python, C/C++, HTML/CSS, Java, SQL, UI/UX

## Languages

English [Professional Working Proficiency], Hindi [Native Proficiency], Bengali [Limited Working Proficiency], French [Elementary Proficiency], German [Fundamental Proficiency]

### Links

LinkedIn, GitHub